<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on Apache OpenServerless™</title><link>/blog/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on Apache OpenServerless™</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/blog/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building MCP Servers the Easy Way with Apache OpenServerless</title><link>/blog/2025/07/08/building-mcp-servers-the-easy-way-with-apache-openserverless/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2025/07/08/building-mcp-servers-the-easy-way-with-apache-openserverless/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s 2025, and apparently, if your infrastructure isn’t running on MCP servers, are you even in tech? From stealth startups to sleepy enterprises pretending to innovate, everyone claims to be “built on MCP” — or at least wishes they were. It’s the new badge of modernity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this guide, I’ll show how to build an MCP-compliant server using Apache OpenServerless and our custom MCP plugin. By deploying OpenServerless and using the plugin, you can quickly expose tools via the Model Context Protocol (MCP). This setup enables fast and portable AI workflows across any cloud or on-prem environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apache OpenServerless is the easiest way to build your cloud native AI application</title><link>/blog/2025/05/15/apache-openserverless-is-the-easiest-way-to-build-your-cloud-native-ai-application/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2025/05/15/apache-openserverless-is-the-easiest-way-to-build-your-cloud-native-ai-application/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have never heard of it, you may wonder: what is Apache OpenServerless?
The short answer is: a portable, self-contained and complete cloud-native serverless platform, built on top of Kubernetes and especially suitable to develop production-ready AI applications with minimal effort. Because of its portability and availability in every environment, including air-gapped ones, it shines when you have strong privacy and security constraints and need to build Private AI applications.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>